{
    "id": "5b844676d5f341a1a731e94ca19bc4c3",
    "title": "Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Bill said that he .................................. the party.",
            "description": "After past reporting verbs, we use past verbs.",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't like",
                "didn't like",
                "didn't liked"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked her ............................... she would marry me.",
            "description": "We use if or whether to report questions.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "if",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The police inspector asked us ............................... our passports.",
            "description": "To report imperatives we use to-infinitives. ",
            "answers": [
                "show",
                "to show",
                "that we show"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I wondered how ...............................",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "are you",
                "you are",
                "were you",
                "you were"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "The government has announced that taxes ............................",
            "description": "After present reporting verbs we normally use present tenses.",
            "answers": [
                "will rise",
                "would be raised",
                "will be raised"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she .............................. enough.",
            "description": "Had had is the reported form of has/have had.",
            "answers": [
                "has had",
                "had had",
                "have",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................ I didn't intend to stand for election.",
            "description": "'That' cannot be dropped after reporting verbs like reply and shout.",
            "answers": [
                "replied",
                "replied that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................................ you are probably right.",
            "description": "The conjunction 'that' can be dropped after common reporting verbs like say and think.",
            "answers": [
                "think",
                "think that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I .................................. I was busy.",
            "description": "The conjunction 'that' cannot be dropped after the reporting verb 'shout'.",
            "answers": [
                "shouted",
                "shouted that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He wanted to know ...................................... leaving.",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "when was I",
                "when I was",
                "when I will"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody told me why ..................................... to sign the papers.",
            "description": "The auxiliary 'do' is not used in reported questions.",
            "answers": [
                "had I",
                "did I have",
                "I had"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew how .............................",
            "description": "The auxiliary 'do' is not used in reported questions and answers.",
            "answers": [
                "you felt",
                "did you feel",
                "you feel"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}